<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Travel on Nandaja.</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/travel/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Travel on Nandaja.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 19:58:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A walk (followed by sleeping on benches) to remember</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2016-12-06-a-walk-followed-by-sitting-and-sleeping-on-benches-and-what-not-to-remember.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2016-12-06-a-walk-followed-by-sitting-and-sleeping-on-benches-and-what-not-to-remember.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am sitting near a fireplace in the outskirts of Threlkeld, a lake&#xA;district village. The view from the window is absolutely breathtaking. I&#xA;can see mist covered farms grazed by sheep, snow clad mountains, winter&#xA;struck trees, and tiny little stone cottages. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but&#xA;contemplate my journey this past couple of weeks around the United&#xA;Kingdom and Ireland and I can&amp;rsquo;t control my urge to write about how&#xA;incredible an adventure it has been. Backpacking in this part of the&#xA;world is very easy in terms of navigating your way through, but not so&#xA;much when it comes to your budget, especially when you have Indian&#xA;Rupees in your bank account(which sadly has hit its record low). But I&#xA;must say, being on a low budget made my journey 10 times interesting -&#xA;thanks to all the incredible people I met along the way who helped me&#xA;out or shared the same low on the budget situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travelling In And Around North India</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 18:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I quit my job, everyone kept asking - ‘So, what next?’ to which I&#xA;politely replied - ‘Nothing decided yet’. In my mind, I already had the&#xA;plan though. I wanted to travel. Where to? I knew that as well. I wanted&#xA;to explore my vast and diverse country. I thought I will finish off my&#xA;country first and then will go on to the South-East Asian countries, as if it is&#xA;even possible to “finish off” seeing India. I have been on the road for&#xA;a couple of months now and I haven’t even scratched the surface of the&#xA;country. Every single place I have been so far had some novelty or other&#xA;to offer. Looking back, this journey has been life changing. The&#xA;experiences I have had - some good and some bad, gave me a lot of&#xA;perspective on my own life. Moreover, I realised how perfectly content I am just&#xA;being with myself. I always used to think I was an introvert. I was a&#xA;bit shy in public and never felt comfortable in a big group. Travelling&#xA;alone, when I got so comfortable being with myself, I started&#xA;getting along with people so well. Someone wise once told me - ‘If you&#xA;are not happy being with yourself, you can never be happy being with&#xA;other people’. I understand what he meant now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Day I Decided to Travel</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2016-01-10-the-day-i-decided-to-travel.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 15:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2016-01-10-the-day-i-decided-to-travel.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was exactly 4 months ago, on the day after I met with an accident and&#xA;was temporarily crippled, which ironically was the day of my 23rd birthday,&#xA;I made the best decision of my life. I decided to&#xA;backpack in Europe as soon as I (literally) get back on my feet and, of course,&#xA;the consulate allows.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I haven&amp;rsquo;t traveled much even with my family, let&#xA;alone solo. I never realized I even had a flair for traveling till last&#xA;year, when I had my little adventure in Rajasthan. Going to Rome has&#xA;been on my bucket list since high school. Also, a bit embarrassing to admit,&#xA;I was scared to death that my parents will get me married to someone&#xA;in an year and I will never get to travel alone again. So on a sunny&#xA;Friday afternoon of September 4th 2015, I decided, just like that, to&#xA;travel to Italy the coming December and experience the European winter&#xA;and Christmas, no matter what. Boy, Am I happy I did!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
