<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://nandaja.space/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>Nandaja</title><link>https://nandaja.space/</link><description>Nandaja's Blog</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 09:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2021-04-17-using-kubeip-to-have statis-ips-in-a-kubernetes-cluster/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2021-04-17-using-kubeip-to-have statis-ips-in-a-kubernetes-cluster/</link><title>Using KubeIP to have static IP in GKE</title><description>This is a small rant about a library I discovered some time ago  at work to use
with our Kubernetes cluster manged by Google Cloud. The library is called Kube
IP and I absolutely love it!Infrastructure on AWS</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2017-03-04-life-as-a-recurser-a-fraction-of-the-whole.markdown/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2017-03-04-life-as-a-recurser-a-fraction-of-the-whole.markdown/</link><title>Life as a Recurser - A fraction of the whole</title><description>I have been living in New York City as one among the incredible Recurse Center community for the past four weeks. Which means one third of my time as a Recurser is behind me and I can't think of a better occasion to blog about RC. I have been procrastinating blogging for so long, but today is the day I finally do it!What is Recurse Center, you ask?</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-12-06-a-walk-followed-by-sitting-and-sleeping-on-benches-and-what-not-to-remember.markdown/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-12-06-a-walk-followed-by-sitting-and-sleeping-on-benches-and-what-not-to-remember.markdown/</link><title>A walk(followed by sitting and sleeping on benches, and what not) to remember</title><description>I am sitting near a fireplace in the outskirts of Threlkeld, a lake
district village. The view from the window is absolutely breathtaking. I
can see mist covered farms grazed by sheep, snow clad mountains, winter
struck trees, and tiny little stone cottages. I can't help but
contemplate my journey this past couple of weeks around the United
Kingdom and Ireland and I can't control my urge to write about how
incredible an adventure it has been. Backpacking in this part of the
world is very easy in terms of navigating your way through, but not so
much when it comes to your budget, especially when you have Indian
Rupees in your bank account(which sadly has hit its record low). But I
must say, being on a low budget made my journey 10 times interesting -
thanks to all the incredible people I met along the way who helped me
out or shared the same low on the budget situation.My journey this time started in Cambridge where I met the rest of the
PeARS team members and had an amazing time working, meeting great people
from the university, exploring Cambridge, and a lot more. We even got to
go up to the roof of King's college chapel(which is a privilege reserved
to the fellows in the King's college), attend the Friday choir service,
enjoyed tea in a room where Alan Turing possibly once did the same, and a
lot more things which will remain in my memories as long as my brain is
in a state to remember things. After our small get-together in
Cambridge, Hrishi and I set out on a
journey to explore the rest of UK. We had the best of times roaming
around London, walking all around Amesbury trying to have a look at
Stonehenge, surviving by eating the apples we plucked out of the trees
on the roadside, trying to hitch rides to save money, walking around the
bays in Cardiff, getting to the port by bus to catch a ferry to Ireland in
the freezing cold in late hours, and crashing with some awesome cool people
in Dublin who were angels in our low budget situation. From there I had
to continue my journey alone since he had to get back home. I traveled around
Ireland hitching, trekking, couchsurfing, drinking, and doing all kinds of
fun stuff. Ireland was a mesmerizing beauty. I think Ireland is
definitely the most beautiful place I have ever seen in my life and
Irish are the nicest of people I have ever met in my life. From Belfast
in Northern Ireland, I again took a ferry to a port in Scotland. I
stayed with an amazing bunch of backpackers in Glasgow, then road-tripped
around the Scottish highlands from Inverness with a couple of guys I met
in the hostel, and then reached Edinburgh.</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-10-30-subjecting-myself-to-a-potential-failure.markdown/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-10-30-subjecting-myself-to-a-potential-failure.markdown/</link><title>Subjecting myself to a potential failure</title><description>I am at a point now where I do not officially have a job. The work I do
right now demands a better grasp on many programming fundamentals and on
a programming language other than Python - preferably JVM based. I am
not a very good programmer or exceptionally intelligent. So I have
decided to invest a huge deal of time and effort to learn what I should
have learned ages ago.Learning Lisp or one of its dialects by reading SICP is something that I
have tried a zillion times starting from my second year in college and
have failed miserably. Another major endeavor that I failed at was
trying to implement all basic and advanced data structures using that
Lisp dialect I just mentioned(Haskell was the obvious choice back then
because, Hey, Lambda calculus!).</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</link><title>Backpacking In And Around North India</title><description>When I quit my job, everyone kept asking - ‘So, what next?’ to which I
politely replied - ‘Nothing decided yet’. In my mind, I already had the
plan though. I wanted to travel. Where to? I knew that as well. I wanted
to explore my vast and diverse country. I thought I will finish off my
country first and then will go on to the South-East Asian countries, as if it is
even possible to “finish off” seeing India. I have been on the road for
a couple of months now and I haven’t even scratched the surface of the
country. Every single place I have been so far had some novelty or other
to offer. Looking back, this journey has been life changing. The
experiences I have had - some good and some bad, gave me a lot of
perspective on my own life. Moreover, I realised how perfectly content I am just
being with myself. I always used to think I was an introvert. I was a
bit shy in public and never felt comfortable in a big group. Travelling
alone, when I got so comfortable being with myself, I started
getting along with people so well. Someone wise once told me - ‘If you
are not happy being with yourself, you can never be happy being with
other people’. I understand what he meant now.Every single memory I made will be cherished eternally, but still I do
have some favourites. Like sleeping in a railway station platform,
riding a bike up in the Himalayas, the trek I did in Pokhara, the 10 day
silent Vipassana meditation retreat(story for a whole new blog
post),celebrating my birthday with some total strangers I met,
hitchhiking in the outskirts of Nepal, the delicious Tibetan bread that
a lady prepared for me inviting me to her abode in Darjeeling, etc.
Unlike my last trip, this time I was working alongside on the project
PeARS[product placement] and it felt so relaxing working by looking at
ever changing landscapes.</description><pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-01-10-the-day-i-decided-to-travel.markdown/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2016-01-10-the-day-i-decided-to-travel.markdown/</link><title>The Day I Decided to Travel</title><description>It was exactly 4 months ago, on the day after I met with an accident and
was temporarily crippled, which ironically was the day of my 23rd birthday,
I made the best decision of my life. I decided to
backpack in Europe as soon as I (literally) get back on my feet and, of course,
the consulate allows.Growing up, I haven't traveled much even with my family, let
alone solo. I never realized I even had a flair for traveling till last
year, when I had my little adventure in Rajasthan. Going to Rome has
been on my bucket list since high school. Also, a bit embarrassing to admit,
I was scared to death that my parents will get me married to someone
in an year and I will never get to travel alone again. So on a sunny
Friday afternoon of September 4th 2015, I decided, just like that, to
travel to Italy the coming December and experience the European winter
and Christmas, no matter what. Boy, Am I happy I did!</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2015-09-18-from-future-import-pears-part-1.markdown/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2015-09-18-from-future-import-pears-part-1.markdown/</link><title>From Future Import PeARS, Part - 1</title><description>PeARS (or Peer-to-peer Agent for Reciprocated Search, if you would prefer that) is a distributed search engine project that I got involved with very recently. It is a very interesting and ambitious idea that Aurelie Herbelot thought of, to make searching more secure, accurate and very much user reliant. For an official intro from the skipper herself head over to her blog. What I am trying to share via this post is the current status of the project, where we see PeARS down the road, how much we would love others to look into the project, and what not. Hopefully the first of many more come. :-)</description><pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2015-09-02-rise-above-the-storm-you-will-find-the-sunshine/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2015-09-02-rise-above-the-storm-you-will-find-the-sunshine/</link><title>Rise above the storm, You will find the sunshine!</title><description>I haven't blogged in the past 2 years. Whenever I thought of blogging, suddenly I realized the topic I want to write about was embarrassingly trivial(not that I used to write about world changing ideas before). Even if somehow I end up making my mind to blog about some random stuff, the next immediate thought would be: 'Who would care?!'This made me not blog all this time, which I regret immensely. Today morning I started reading couple of my old blog posts and Boy, Was it entertaining! In some of them I was extremely naive, where as in some I was just plain dumb. As the blog posts progressed in time, I was changing in a lot many ways for good or for bad. When it ended I was so sad and so mad at myself for not blogging in the past one year specifically as this year has been one of my bests in this 23 years of existence. I have done stuff and seen stuff that I never thought I would do and see. I wish I had blogged about them right then and there. There has been storms and rains over which I rose. Can't say I have seen the sunshine yet, but I am sure I will soon.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-08-26-gsoc-weeklystatus-update-9/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-08-26-gsoc-weeklystatus-update-9/</link><title>GSoC Weekly update #9</title><description>The work of mine has been correcting the reference glyph files and developing a web interface for the proposed framework. I had tried and made the reference files least buggy as possible. I have gone through the glyph names of almost all the 243 words in 4 fonts. I had to invest a lot of time on this especially due to one minor misunderstanding of mine on the multiple correct renderings of the words. And I hope it will get much refined after Rajeeshettan proof read it for 2 fonts as he has suggested.
(I have changed the renderings of words with repham in Rachana such that the dotreph comes first. So words like these http://troll.ws/image/2e3a872e, http://troll.ws/image/469dd87a, http://troll.ws/image/5838dbec although looks correct, will be in the wrongly rendered words list by harfbuzz.)The next part of this weeks work was developing the web interface (Excuse my poor design, I am cleaning it up as I write). It doesn't actually spits output to the user now or doesn't make it easier for the user to open files. I am hoping to make it run the script well in a week's time and don't think it is ready yet for the review. So I would like another week to make it ready for reviewing.</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-08-17-gsoc-weekly-status-update-8/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-08-17-gsoc-weekly-status-update-8/</link><title>GSoC Weekly update #8</title><description>I have changed the framework interface from its previous form, although the previous front end automated_rendering_testing.py is still present in the repo. Now the new interface, rendering_testing.py, need all the file names to be provided as command line arguments. The user gets the convenience  of using the tab completion this way. The user will have to give as command line arguments 6 files (font  file, test cases file, reference file, rendering output and files to store output) and an optional directory name(if the engine is harfbuzz).If the rendering engine is harfbuzz, user can run the script generate_hb_rendering.py  along with the test cases file and font file as parameters, to create the rendered output file. If that is not the case, the user will have to create this file as well in the prescribed form.</description><pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-08-11-gsoc-weekly-update-6/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-08-11-gsoc-weekly-update-6/</link><title>GSoC Weekly update #6</title><description>The past two weeks has been a blur with a lot of travelling and minimal Internet access. The following are the works I have been doing so far:The following modifications were asked to be made on the existing framework by my mentor after a Hangout session as part of the evaluations:</description><pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-07-28-gsoc-weekly-update-5/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-07-28-gsoc-weekly-update-5/</link><title>GSoC Weekly update #5</title><description>The works this week has been a little slow with college exams and assignments. This is what I have done so far this week.I have completed the list of reference files containing glyph names of 243 words from four fonts each. Fonts being: Rachana, Meera, Suruma and Lohit-Malayalaam.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-07-20-gsoc-weekly-report-4/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-07-20-gsoc-weekly-report-4/</link><title>GSoC Weekly update #4</title><description>This week my main task was to migrate my code to Python. As of now I have implemented my algorithm in Python. Here is the link to the repo : https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-TestingI have expanded my test cases' list a bit. Now it has 243 Malayalam words. I have manually created files with glyph names of these test cases in four fonts: Rachana, Meera, Suruma and Lohith-Malayalam in files names rachana-glyph.txt,  meera-glyph.txt etc. (It is still a bit buggy, so haven't pushed the latest commit of this yet).</description><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-07-14-gsoc-weekly-update-3/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-07-14-gsoc-weekly-update-3/</link><title>GSoC Weekly update #3</title><description>This week I've been working on generating a baseline glyphs file for 4 fonts: Rachana, Meera, Suruma and Lohith-Malayalam. I have selected some malayalam words from harfbuzz tree and Santhosh Thottingal's test cases which I thought would be enough to test rendering problems. Then I started listing the glyph names of these files for each fonts in separate text files. To get the corresponding Unicode code point of each word, I wrote a small Java code. So I executed the script on each word, found all the code points and made 4 text files that contains the corresponding glyph names of the four fonts I mentioned earlier.Although my mentor did tell me that it is not possible to generate glyph names automatically, I wasted more than a couple of days on a Font Forge script to make it automatically output the glyph names. But that gives the glyph name only if we click on each character, which became terribly disappointing. So instead I used it to make the baseline glyphs file in the structure I want if I click on the necessary characters. But this code is trivial as far as rendering testing is concerned and will leave it out from now (Just noting it down as it wasted a very non-trivial amount of my time ;-) ).</description><pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-06-29-gsoc-weekly-update-2/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-06-29-gsoc-weekly-update-2/</link><title>GSoC Weekly update #2</title><description>Coding period for GSoC has started the past week and I have been working on a very simple implementation of the proposal in C and two tiny bash scripts. My code is available here: https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-TestingThe first thing to be done to test using these scripts is create a file that contains a set of words to be tested to see if their rendering is correct. Here I have taken a sample test data file created by SMC a while ago (ml-harfbuzz-testdata,txt). Now pass this file through the script render_test.sh along with the necessary font file. That is:</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-06-10-gsoc-community-engagement-period/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-06-10-gsoc-community-engagement-period/</link><title>GSoC - Community engagement period</title><description>GSoC 2013 approved project list was published on May 27th and the community engagement period was started from May 29th onwards. During this period the students are supposed to bond with their mentors, read the documentations and finalize your plans so you can have a head start with your project. The project topic for which I have got accepted for is "Automated rendering testing" and I will be completing that project under Swathanthra Malayalam Computing. I could learn a lot a new stuff so far during this community bonding period with a heavy deal of help from my mentor Rajeesh K Nambiar, although I haven't started actual coding yet. I will try to explain my proposal status and further steps here, in detail.Basically, my project idea is to create an automated way to test the rendering of Indic fonts by rendering engines like harfbuzz. The procedure I wish to follow here is quite simple. Create a test file that contains a set of words, mostly characters with ligatures that will be used for testing the rendering. Along with that I will be maintaining a file that contain the glyph infos of the words/characters in the test file for a particular font, say Malayalam font Rachana. As of now I am preparing it manually, can switch to font forge scripts if required.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-04-29-bangalore-diaries/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-04-29-bangalore-diaries/</link><title>Bangalore Diaries</title><description>I remember times when I used to eagerly wait for my school final exams to get through with, so that I can enjoy the long summer holidays that follows. I have been missing that feeling for a while now. But this year I was impatiently waiting for summer to arrive because I knew what was waiting for me this summer season. A long month ahead filled with knowledge, fun and freedom. An internship in Bangalore! But once  I reached Bangalore city, I could feel that my all my excitement was turning into ashes. My nerves started kicking in (As it always does) and I started wondering 'What the heck am I doing here?'. I am joining as a temp intern in this cool Australian Software company called Bang the table . I don't know Ruby on Rails or even Ruby without which basically all I am eligible to apply for is probably the post of an office boy/girl (Which is already taken, FYI). I got a small place (very small) to live which I knew I would love from the first sight of it and got three amazing roommates, who have been trying so hard to make my Hindi speaking skills better till date.So I joined my office exactly on April 1st ( Which date could be more appropriate than this, eh? ). All the faces were extremely welcoming and warm, and some of which quite familiar too, most of them being mallu faces. I had great fun shooting people with laser guns on my first day itself. Thanks to Ershad for his awesome birthday treat. My timing was just perfect.</description><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-03-11-minidebconf-at-nit-c/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-03-11-minidebconf-at-nit-c/</link><title>MiniDebConf at NIT-C</title><description>Ever since I started loving FOSS, I really wanted to attend a FOSSMeet. And last month I got extremely lucky and could attend FOSSMeet at NIT-C. This year along with FOSSMeet a MiniDebConf was also arranged. A month prior to it, I was asked to give a Ruby gem packaging session at this MiniDebConf. I was quite nervous because this was the first FOSS event I ever attended and I was asked to give a session. But I knew it would be a great experience, So I decided to go with it.FOSSMeet was conducted from 22nd to 24th of February and my session was scheduled for 24th. I reached Calicut town on 23rd morning (Obviously unprepared) and when I was just about to hop into a bus to NIT, one of the MiniDebConf organizers, Vipin called me and said that my session was preponed to that day afternoon. I started freaking out because I still had to prepare slides and decide what all to include in my session. As soon as I reached NIT, I had to go to my relatives' place at the NIT apartments, where I was supposed to stay for the next two days ( I preferred hostel, but whatever!). After that I rushed to NIT campus, got my speaker's ID card from the registration counter and started roaming around the campus searching for the MiniDebConf venue. Finally I found that it was going on at the networks lab and got there. When I entered Pavi and Shirish were giving talks on debian releases and stuff and I quite honestly didn't know how to introduce myself. 'Hey, I am Nandaja. I am a speaker here' didn't sound polite enough. So I followed a guy, who assigned me a system in the lab thinking I am a delegate there. So I sat there and started preparing slides for my session until the lunch break.  Once I reached the hall were lunch was being served, I decided to socialize. I met some cool SMC people who were really easy going and friendly and then I met Praveen, whom I was more than happy to meet. After the lunch, we went back to the NSL lab and there Praveen introduced me to Shirish and Pavi, two Debian gurus. It was the time for Debian installation workshop. Pavi asked me to help the delegates with the partitioning and stuff, which I tried doing and I don't think the students who listened understood much. We clapped for the teams who successfully completed the installation. The session lasted till evening and it was supper time soon after. So my packaging session was again rescheduled for the next day. I again met some cool geeks there. There was a really nice Aaron Swartz memorial talk by Vishnu later that night. Following that was hack night and a talk by Praveen on open source contributions. It was getting too late and had to get back to the relatives' place. So I missed it (The reason why I preferred hostel).</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-01-07-patching-using-quilt/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2013-01-07-patching-using-quilt/</link><title>Patching using quilt</title><description>Patch files are files used to apply changes to the source code of a computer program. These changes may be for fixing bugs or for extending functionality. Quilt is a software utility for managing patches. Quilt is highly used among Linux kernal developers for managing patches. I started using quilt when I had to patch a piece of code while I was packaging for debian. Debian source packages usually use quilt. It has been incorporated into dpkg (Debian's package manager).So, Let's say you downloaded a debian package and found a bug in it. So you will have to create a patch and send it to the Debian developers for their review and approval.</description><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-22-anti-virus-for-linux/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-22-anti-virus-for-linux/</link><title>Anti virus for Linux</title><description>Using an anti virus software in my Linux machine is something that I have not given much thought to. I know for the fact that the odds for a Linux system to get affected by a malware is pretty low. As of my understanding, the fact that Linux systems use open source software is a big bonus here. I mean, why would some one bother in sitting and writing a harmful program when everyone can see your code. Also crackers aim at a much elaborate target. I am sure they have better things to do than messing with some Linux users, which is only 2% of world computer users' population. Still, there are executable files that may get into your system via mails or flash drives. But in Linux, nothing will happen if you simply double click an executable file (provided you don't have Wine installed). It won't get executed unless you give it permission for execution. This is much unlikely to happen as Linux users are supposed to know what they are doing (Myself excluded!). And of course, there are many more reasons like user privileges, simplicity of kernal, etc.But this doesn't mean that we don't need an anti virus software installed. For instance, as in my case, I thought of  using an anti virus software when my windows using friends started blaming me for spreading malwares via flash drives. And also, being a music junkie, I constantly give my phone a hard time copying downloaded files to it from my computer.</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-15-quick-tip-installing-a-package-in-linux-using-run-files/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-15-quick-tip-installing-a-package-in-linux-using-run-files/</link><title>Quick tip: Installing a software in linux using files in .run format</title><description>The .run files are binary executable files. These files need to be executed to install the software. Such files are often considered as unsafe as we cannot find a way to uninstall them and we cannot say what the code will do to your system. But some games and apps are available that are packaged in this file format. Installing using .run file is rather easy.First of all download the required .run file.</description><pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-10-recovering-lost-password-in-ubuntu-12-04/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-10-recovering-lost-password-in-ubuntu-12-04/</link><title>Recovering lost password in Ubuntu 12.04</title><description>Yesterday, While I was trying to help my friend with his lost Ubuntu password, I explored the following two methods to do this quite easily.First method is using the recovery mode. This method is pretty simple.</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-09-gnu-project-debugger/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-09-gnu-project-debugger/</link><title>GNU Project Debugger</title><description>Today I came across a very nifty tool on my linux system. It is GNU Project Debugger a.k.a GDB. It is the standard debugger in UNIX. It lets you poke around your program and find out what is wrong with your program, if it crashed or gave you unexpected results. It can be used to debug programs written in Ada, Java, Pascal etc.( Although I haven't tried it yet on anything other than C programs). So, yeah, it is a very powerful tool. I played around with it for a little while and it seems pretty easy. I am sure if I give it a little more effort, I sure can make best friends with GDB pretty soon. I wish I knew  GDB six months ago when I kept getting segmentation faults in my Data structures lab.</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-02-perl-warning-setting-locale-failed/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-12-02-perl-warning-setting-locale-failed/</link><title>perl: warning: Setting locale failed. - Fixed</title><description>Today when I was trying to build a package on a Debian VPS, It started reporting really annoying messages like these:</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-11-30-debian-packaging/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-11-30-debian-packaging/</link><title>Debian Packaging</title><description>Once you've picked a Gem and filed the ITP, it is time for you to start packaging. For this first run the command:gem2deb </description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-11-29-diaspora-packaging-for-debian/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-11-29-diaspora-packaging-for-debian/</link><title>Diaspora Packaging For Debian</title><description>Here are the steps I followed while  packaging diaspora for debian.My ultimate guide for debian-diaspora packaging has been this piratepad document :</description><pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-11-02-diaspora-im-lovin-it/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-11-02-diaspora-im-lovin-it/</link><title>Diaspora</title><description>Howdy,
Social networking is an experience that most of us do love. The most recent addition to this colossal world of social networking is diaspora.Diaspora is a free personalized web server that can be installed and implemented as a distributed social network. In simple words, we own our own social networking site (More or less) . Unlike the other social networking sites, where the members are treated as mere products,in diaspora we are our own masters. Many pods/servers are maintained by numerous private groups/ individuals all around the world. We can create our account in any one of them or we can opt to run our own pod. And as it is distributed, We can connect to people with account in any other pods. Pretty cool, huh?</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-10-30-helloworld/</guid><link>https://nandaja.space/posts-output/2012-10-30-helloworld/</link><title>Hello, World!</title><description>Blogging! Not my cup of tea, probably. But still giving it a try.Cheers.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate></item></channel></rss>