<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bangalore on Nandaja.</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/bangalore/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bangalore on Nandaja.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 20:58:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/bangalore/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Diaries</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2013-04-29-bangalore-diaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 20:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2013-04-29-bangalore-diaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember times when I used to eagerly wait for my school final exams to get through with, so that I can enjoy the long summer holidays that follows. I have been missing that feeling for a while now. But this year I was impatiently waiting for summer to arrive because I knew what was waiting for me this summer season. A long month ahead filled with knowledge, fun and freedom. An internship in Bangalore! But once  I reached Bangalore city, I could feel that my all my excitement was turning into ashes. My nerves started kicking in (As it always does) and I started wondering &amp;lsquo;What the heck am I doing here?&amp;rsquo;. I am joining as a temp intern in this cool Australian Software company called &lt;a href=&#34;http://bangthetable.com&#34;&gt;Bang the table&lt;/a&gt; . I don&amp;rsquo;t know Ruby on Rails or even Ruby without which basically all I am eligible to apply for is probably the post of an office boy/girl (Which is already taken, FYI). I got a small place (very small) to live which I knew I would love from the first sight of it and got three amazing roommates, who have been trying so hard to make my Hindi speaking skills better till date.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
