<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Debian on Nandaja.</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/debian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Debian on Nandaja.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 18:26:05 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/debian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Debian Packaging</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2012-11-30-debian-packaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 18:26:05 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2012-11-30-debian-packaging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve picked a Gem and filed the ITP, it is time for you to start packaging. For this first run the command:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gem2deb &lt;Gem name&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;gem2deb is actually the Ruby Debian packaging suite. It is a set of tools to create Debian packages from Ruby software distributed with RubyGems. It will automatically run the tests for Ruby1.8 and Ruby1.9 as well. For running these tests gem2deb look for a Rakefile or a .rb file or a .Yaml file inside the debian directory. Running these tests successfully has always been a headache for me. Still not at all good at it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Diaspora Packaging For Debian</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2012-11-29-diaspora-packaging-for-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 22:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2012-11-29-diaspora-packaging-for-debian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps I followed while  packaging diaspora for debian.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My ultimate guide for debian-diaspora packaging has been this piratepad document :&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://piratepad.net/tu0H1eU2vH&#34;&gt;http://piratepad.net/tu0H1eU2vH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diaspora is built on Ruby on Rails platform. In Ruby programming language, the software packages are called &amp;lsquo;RubyGems&amp;rsquo; or simply &amp;lsquo;Gems&amp;rsquo;. Gems contain a packaged Ruby application or library. So basically our task is to convert this RubyGem into debian file format.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are numerous number of gems upon which diaspora is depending. To complete the debian packaging of whole diaspora software we will have to package each and every one of these gems. So our first step towards packaging is select a gem which is a dependency for diaspora and that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been packaged yet. You can easily pick one from the above mentioned pirate pad document.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
