<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Nandaja.</title>
    <link>http://localhost:60425/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Nandaja.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 19:58:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://localhost:60425/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Using KubeIP to have static IP in GKE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2021-04-17-using-kubeip-to-have-statis-ips-in-a-kubernetes-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2021-04-17-using-kubeip-to-have-statis-ips-in-a-kubernetes-cluster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a small rant about a library I discovered some time ago  at work to use
with our Kubernetes cluster manged by Google Cloud. The library is called &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubeip.com/&#34; title=&#34;Kube IP&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kube
IP&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and I absolutely love it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;infrastructure-on-aws&#34;&gt;Infrastructure on AWS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At my current work(which I will be leaving in 2 weeks to be exact), I started
maintaining a cloud managed Kubernetes cluster(GKE) some 6 months ago. Kubenetes
felt like the right kind of tool for our infrastructure needs and so far it has
been a really thrilling experience. Before this we used to use AWS exclusively
and used to have containarized apps deployed in separate EC2 instances. This
turned out slightly more expensive and resulted in a lot of resource waste. All
of these machines were inside a public subnet in a VPC. We had a big PostgreSQL
database to which all of the aforementioned apps communicated with. The design
decision I took was to use AWS RDS for the database server and keep it in a
private subnet under the same VPC. I added inbound rules on the security group
to allow connections to the EC2 instances in the VPC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;kubernetes-migrationalso-aws-to-gcp-migration&#34;&gt;Kubernetes migration(also AWS to GCP migration)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I decided to move all the above containerized apps to Kubernetes(which was
a long process), the next design choice was to decide what to do about the
database. Migrating the database to Cloud SQL(the managed database service of
GCP) felt like a lot of work especially since we were majorly short staffed. Instead I decided
to keep the DB over at AWS. Opening the DB to the Internet so the K8s cluster
can communicate with it felt like a death wish. So instead I decided to keep it
private and whitelist the IP addresses of the Source IP of the requests from the
Kubernetes Cluster. I expose each deployment on the cluster with a ClusterIP
Service type and used an nginx-ingress controller to open up the services to the
Internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-sad-story-of-ephemeral-node-ips&#34;&gt;The sad story of ephemeral node IPs&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I noticed that the Source IP of the requests from the pod was
the IP address of the node it was deployed in. My mind went -
&amp;ldquo;Easy! Just whitelist those IPs!&amp;rdquo;. Oh boy, was I wrong! I understood that the IP
addresses of the nodes kept changing since they were ephemeral in nature. I
thought that the best way to solve this problem was to reserve static IPs for the
nodes in the cluster. I painfully realized that the nodes of the cluster kept
changing(auto-scaling,etc. like it should), along which changes the IP address.
A lot of looking up time later I found this wonderful library called &lt;em&gt;Kube IP&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;kube-ip-to-the-rescue&#34;&gt;Kube IP to the rescue&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The idea was quite simple. I deploy KubeIP in a separate nodepool in the
cluster, and configure it to monitor another nodepool which I expect to have
staic IP addresses. I have to reserve n-number of static IP addresses first on
Google Cloud and give them a label that I configure KubeIP with. KubeIP pod will
monitor for any event on the Kubernetes API that signals a removal or addition of
nodes to the nodepool it is monitoring. Once it records am addition to the
nodepool, it forces the node to have an IP address from the reserved static IP
list which is not used by any of the nodes. So far this has been working out
great for me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One thing that was kind of going wrong for me at the beginning was that the pods
gets scheduled in the KubeIP nodepool (I guess this was my lack of understanding
of kubernetes). The way I solved it was I tainted the nodes in the
KubeIP node pool with a NoExecute taint accompanied with a specific Key Value. I made
the KubeIP pod tolerant to this taint value and everything worked smoothly. The
documentation for &lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/docs/concepts/scheduling-eviction/taint-and-toleration/&#34;&gt;taints and
tolerations&lt;/a&gt;
is very descriptive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The documentaion of KubeIP tool is very well done and I am starting to look into
the codebase of the tool. I am counting this as part of my Go explorations. I
will document how my first impression of reading Go code was in another post. I
know that I have so much more to learn about Kubernetes and may be there is a
better/cleaner/cheaper way to deal with the problem I was having. I hope to keep
learning a bit each day. But in the meantime, here is to small victories! :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fin.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life as a Recurser - A fraction of the whole</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2017-03-04-life-as-a-recurser-a-fraction-of-the-whole.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Mar 2017 01:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2017-03-04-life-as-a-recurser-a-fraction-of-the-whole.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been living in New York City as one among the incredible Recurse Center community for the past four weeks. Which means one third of my time as a Recurser is behind me and I can&amp;rsquo;t think of a better occasion to blog about RC. I have been procrastinating blogging for so long, but today is the day I finally do it!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.recurse.com/&#34;&gt;Recurse Center&lt;/a&gt;, you ask?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Recurse Center is a free, self-directed, educational retreat for
people who want to get better at programming, whether they&amp;rsquo;ve been
coding for three decades or three months.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But so far, RC has been that and a lot more for me. After the first
week&amp;rsquo;s panic of overwhelming experiences(living in New York City,
sharing a hipster looking workspace with extremely talented people from
all around the world,
planning what to focus on during my time here, etc. to name a few),
RC has turned out to be one of the best experiences I have ever had in
my life. I learn from the nicest and coolest bunch of nerds I have ever
met, I live with two amazing fellow Recursers, and I live in the biggest
city in the world! What more can I ask for?!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Getting in the learning mode was not easy. After all that globe
trotting, it took some serious effort to get back to programming and to
decide what to work on. After a lot of talking with people and
thinking, I decided to make my computer science foundations stronger
first. While I was at it, I decided to pick up a new programming
language. Since I was thinking about re-writing the DHT part of PeARS in
another programming language, it felt right to pick up Erlang which has
amazing concurrency support. Erlang syntax didn&amp;rsquo;t appeal me much, so I
decided to go with Elixir and turns out it works great in a distributed
setup. I have solved a lot of algorithms, implemented couple of
interesting data structures, etc. in Elixir so far and I think I am
getting a hang of the language. Alongside, I am catching up with all
the reading that I have been putting off. I read books
on Algorithms &amp;amp; Data Structures, High performance Python, Metaprogramming
in Elixir, Purely functional Data Structures(starting to, i.e.), etc. I
attend some very interesting study groups like Python study group,
algorithms study group, a white paper a week study group(YES!!), 7
databases for 7 weeks study groups, etc. I am in the process of figuring
out if I can write a transpiler for Python byte code to work on BEAM(The
Erlang VM).
It is a bit ambitious since one is stack based and the other is register
based, but I am researching the possibilities and I have people around
to help.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best thing about RC isn&amp;rsquo;t just learning, it is collaborative
learning. I pair programmed with people on a lot of code I wrote, and it
has influenced the way I write code and the way I think while
doing it. I now do TDD which I always was too lazy to do. I now think in
the functional way when coding and it make even my Python code cleaner.
It has been great to know and learn what other people are working on
at least to know my options. An open mind is something I packed with me
, but I am trying hard not to lose focus on the
things I want to accomplish by myself. I sometimes feel like I don&amp;rsquo;t do
much and that I get too side tracked but the fact that I keep learning
and working makes me happy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:60425/img/RC.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;A usual Thursday evening at RC&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t get the wrong impression that RC is just about learning 24/7 and
burning yourself out. We have a lot of social events happening
throughout the week. The RC alums drops by every Thursday and that&amp;rsquo;s a
lot of fun. We have game nights with Pizza and beer. And did I mention
that we have a3 day weekend? We hang out outside the RC and sometimes even do the touristic
site-seeing things, although the weather hasn&amp;rsquo;t
totally been in our favor. Believe it or not, it is actually snowing
outside! In the middle of march! I am not complaining though. It is
cherry on top of the cake for me since this is the first time I am
actually seeing snow showers! Also, I take kick-boxings lessons here. So
much fun!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:60425/img/kick-boxing.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s just the way we roll. ;-)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So things I look forward to doing in the next 8 weeks - Spring in New York(!!)
Having a lot of fun, working on my transpiler, implementing things from Purely functional data
structures, attending the interview prep on Fridays, building a web
development framework in Elixir, implementing a lot more of the exotic data
structures and algorithms, and anything else that might please me. :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So long!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A walk (followed by sleeping on benches) to remember</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-12-06-a-walk-followed-by-sitting-and-sleeping-on-benches-and-what-not-to-remember.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-12-06-a-walk-followed-by-sitting-and-sleeping-on-benches-and-what-not-to-remember.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am sitting near a fireplace in the outskirts of Threlkeld, a lake
district village. The view from the window is absolutely breathtaking. I
can see mist covered farms grazed by sheep, snow clad mountains, winter
struck trees, and tiny little stone cottages. I can&amp;rsquo;t help but
contemplate my journey this past couple of weeks around the United
Kingdom and Ireland and I can&amp;rsquo;t control my urge to write about how
incredible an adventure it has been. Backpacking in this part of the
world is very easy in terms of navigating your way through, but not so
much when it comes to your budget, especially when you have Indian
Rupees in your bank account(which sadly has hit its record low). But I
must say, being on a low budget made my journey 10 times interesting -
thanks to all the incredible people I met along the way who helped me
out or shared the same low on the budget situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My journey this time started in Cambridge where I met the rest of the
PeARS team members and had an amazing time working, meeting great people
from the university, exploring Cambridge, and a lot more. We even got to
go up to the roof of King&amp;rsquo;s college chapel(which is a privilege reserved
to the fellows in the King&amp;rsquo;s college), attend the Friday choir service,
enjoyed tea in a room where Alan Turing possibly once did the same, and a
lot more things which will remain in my memories as long as my brain is
in a state to remember things. After our small get-together in
Cambridge, &lt;a href=&#34;http://stultus.in&#34;&gt;Hrishi&lt;/a&gt; and I set out on a
journey to explore the rest of UK. We had the best of times roaming
around London, walking all around Amesbury trying to have a look at
Stonehenge, surviving by eating the apples we plucked out of the trees
on the roadside, trying to hitch rides to save money, walking around the
bays in Cardiff, getting to the port by bus to catch a ferry to Ireland in
the freezing cold in late hours, and crashing with some awesome cool people
in Dublin who were angels in our low budget situation. From there I had
to continue my journey alone since he had to get back home. I traveled around
Ireland hitching, trekking, couchsurfing, drinking, and doing all kinds of
fun stuff. Ireland was a mesmerizing beauty. I think Ireland is
definitely the most beautiful place I have ever seen in my life and
Irish are the nicest of people I have ever met in my life. From Belfast
in Northern Ireland, I again took a ferry to a port in Scotland. I
stayed with an amazing bunch of backpackers in Glasgow, then road-tripped
around the Scottish highlands from Inverness with a couple of guys I met
in the hostel, and then reached Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All I wrote so far was a build up for the beautiful, mighty old
Edinburgh. It is not because Edinburgh was the best of my whole trip,
but the most interesting thing happened in Edinburgh. So here it
goes&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After my incredible journey around the Scottish highlands, I arrived at
Edinburgh after a 5 hour bus journey - tired, famished and desperately in
need for a bed. I walked half an hour from the bus station to get to the
hostel I&amp;rsquo;ve reserved a bed in, for 8 pounds a night. As it turned out I
got all the dates wrong and booked it for the next day. So there I was,
on a Saturday night in Edinburgh with no place to stay and freezing.
Initially I thought it could be  nice thing after all. It is one of the
safest cities in the world. I could just walk about the whole night,
enjoying the night life, saving the 8 Pounds, and check in the next day.
Boy, was I wrong! I got out, started walking outside to realize how cold it was.
My spirits went down and I decided to try in some other hostels in the
area. I started hopping from one hostel to another only to realize that
most places were fully booked due to the weekend tourists and the rest
were charging humongous sums of money for a night(The highest was 50
pounds a night! For a bed! In a hostel!). To tell you the truth, I
didn&amp;rsquo;t have that much money left for the rest of my trip. So I
again started walking and came face to face with the harsh truth that I
was stranded in the city of Edinburgh in that bone chilling cold. After
what felt like an eternity of walking(my watch said I only walked for an
hour, but I was so damn sure that it was wrong!), I heard an angel
singing &amp;ldquo;Shine on you crazy diamond&amp;rdquo; from somewhere. I walked and walked to
find out where the angel is singing from to finally arrive in front of a
pub where there was live music going on. There were bouncers in front of
it, from whom I got to know that the pub is open till 3 O&amp;rsquo;clock in the
morning. A roof above my head till 3AM! I immediately went inside and
ordered myself the cheapest beer they had, which wasn&amp;rsquo;t that cheap
though. Then the party crowd arrived, most of them were very drunk(so
very nice). I started talking and even dancing, and more drinking. In effect
I spent more than what I would have spent in my supposed hostel booking.
The crowd was too much and I decided to get out. From one of the
bouncers, I got to know that the railway station will be open all night
and I can sleep on a bench there. I reached the railway station at half
past 2 only to realize that they close it at 12 O&amp;rsquo;clock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started walking again, badly in need to urinate and saw a McDonald&amp;rsquo;s
that was open and packed with a lot of drunken Scottish people. I went
straight in, ordered myself a cheeseburger and a coffee(I was hungry and
cold) and used their facilities. Even McDonald&amp;rsquo;s had bouncers and I
started talking with them. I helped them in cleaning after the mess the party
people made. But unfortunately it was about to close and I had to hit
the road again. The situation outside was very interesting. People
shouting, throwing up, snogging, peeing, etc. I found a nice little bench
near a park and decided to spend the rest of the night there. It was
almost half past 3 by then. I took out my Kindle and started reading
Notes from a small Island by Bill Bryson. He always brings my spirits
up. Ironically, the part that my Kindle showed was the one when Bill
Bryson is in Dover, with no place to stay and trying to get some sleep
on a bench. The Universe was screwing with me big time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Drunken Scottish people offer all kind of things, if they see you on a
roadside bench in the middle of the night. These things can range from
drinks, smokes, drugs, kisses, to more non-materialistic things like
peace of mind, enlightenment, and ecstasy(or does it belong to the first
category?), but no one offered a place to stay. I decided to walk again
because it was too cold just to sit there. I walked and walked. I helped
people with useful information like where they can throw-up, urinate,
find a bus, etc. because I have seen them all. I finally arrived at
another McDonald&amp;rsquo;s which is open 24 hours. The place was again packed,
but I decided to get another coffee and sit there till dawn. I got a
coffee and found a place in the far end so no one would notice. To my
dismay, a bouncer did notice and asked me to leave(it was very
humiliating, of course). I again started walking. The clock was hitting
5 now. Almost there, I thought. I saw a guy walking with a lot of
takeaway food and soft drinks in his hand(more than what he could handle), biting on his
room key. I asked him if he wanted some help. He said yes and immediately
asked how much do I want. He thought I was a homeless person trying to
get some money from somewhere for my next beer. I politely let him know
that I was just homeless for that particular night and he accepted my
offer to help him for free(Should have charged him 10 pounds!). When we
were walking he said they were having an after party at his place and
asked me to join them. How bad can it be, I decided to go in. His
friends were 5 Scots in their early 20s, 2 girls and 3 boys, who were very drunk.
Two girls were spooning with a guy, and one of the girls was topless.
Another guy was wearing the girl&amp;rsquo;s bra and dancing. It was a very
interesting group of people. They offered me some expensive drink which
I politely declined. One of the girls started talking to me how much
she wants to do &amp;ldquo;world travel&amp;rdquo;, which is the reason why she dropped out
of colleges thrice. I listened to all of their ramblings till half past 6 and
then took my leave(to my great relief). It was morning, and birds were
chirping and my miseries were coming to an end. I went back to my first
hostel and they let me in to the warmth of their sitting room. And I
survived the night&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re still with me, please get your dates right and Don&amp;rsquo;t Panic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I only have one more week to go on this trip, so I doubt if I will have such
interesting experiences in the days to come. Thank goodness for that!
Bye for now. I should get back to my tea and the incredible view now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peace.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subjecting myself to a potential failure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-10-30-subjecting-myself-to-a-potential-failure.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Oct 2016 16:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-10-30-subjecting-myself-to-a-potential-failure.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am at a point now where I do not officially have a job. The work I do
right now demands a better grasp on many programming fundamentals and on
a programming language other than Python - preferably JVM based. I am
not a very good programmer or exceptionally intelligent. So I have
decided to invest a huge deal of time and effort to learn what I should
have learned ages ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learning Lisp or one of its dialects by reading SICP is something that I
have tried a zillion times starting from my second year in college and
have failed miserably. Another major endeavor that I failed at was
trying to implement all basic and advanced data structures using that
Lisp dialect I just mentioned(Haskell was the obvious choice back then
because, Hey, Lambda calculus!).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have decided to try this again this time. I got really inspired by Eli
Bendersky&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;http://eli.thegreenplace.net/tag/sicp&#34;&gt;notes&lt;/a&gt;
that he made during his &amp;rsquo;taming SICP&amp;rsquo; endeavor. I am
going to start SICP again by solving the problems in Clojure instead of
Scheme. Why I&amp;rsquo;m so caught upon a Lisp, you ask? The first thing I ever
read about functional programming languages is the way, in pure
functional programming, the programs are written with such abstraction
that it is like a black box, doing operation without worrying or caring
about the outside world, without any side effects. This sounded very
appealing to me. Also, someone told me Lisp is not for me, but for real
geeks(I promise, this is just a tertiary or a quaternary reason).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think Clojure is a beautiful looking language. Fell in love with the
way it binds arguments to functions using square brackets at the very
first sight. It is JVM based and suits perfectly for the &lt;a
href=&#34;http://pearsearch.org&#34;&gt;PeARS&lt;/a&gt;
requirements. Also, I was mind blown by the talks given by Rich Hickey.
Hands down the best programming talks I&amp;rsquo;ve ever listened to(Check it out
if you haven&amp;rsquo;t yet. Please. Starting &lt;a
href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=rI8tNMsozo0&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, maybe?).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So this is me putting myself out there. The game plan is laid:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start reading the book, of course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solve the problems using Clojure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Implement some algorithms and data structures in Clojure(I started learning Clojure a bit back).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make notes every weak and publish. Even if it is - &amp;ldquo;I am such a loser, didn&amp;rsquo;t do anything this week&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;P.S.&lt;/b&gt; The title might come out very pessimistic. But I love it when I
rise above the expectations, even when it&amp;rsquo;s my own. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travelling In And Around North India</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 18:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I quit my job, everyone kept asking - ‘So, what next?’ to which I
politely replied - ‘Nothing decided yet’. In my mind, I already had the
plan though. I wanted to travel. Where to? I knew that as well. I wanted
to explore my vast and diverse country. I thought I will finish off my
country first and then will go on to the South-East Asian countries, as if it is
even possible to “finish off” seeing India. I have been on the road for
a couple of months now and I haven’t even scratched the surface of the
country. Every single place I have been so far had some novelty or other
to offer. Looking back, this journey has been life changing. The
experiences I have had - some good and some bad, gave me a lot of
perspective on my own life. Moreover, I realised how perfectly content I am just
being with myself. I always used to think I was an introvert. I was a
bit shy in public and never felt comfortable in a big group. Travelling
alone, when I got so comfortable being with myself, I started
getting along with people so well. Someone wise once told me - ‘If you
are not happy being with yourself, you can never be happy being with
other people’. I understand what he meant now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every single memory I made will be cherished eternally, but still I do
have some favourites. Like sleeping in a railway station platform,
riding a bike up in the Himalayas, the trek I did in Pokhara, the 10 day
silent Vipassana meditation retreat(story for a whole new blog
post),celebrating my birthday with some total strangers I met,
hitchhiking in the outskirts of Nepal, the delicious Tibetan bread that
a lady prepared for me inviting me to her abode in Darjeeling, etc.
Unlike my last trip, this time I was working alongside on the project
PeARS[&lt;a href=&#34;http://pearsearch.org&#34;&gt;product placement&lt;/a&gt;] and it felt so relaxing working by looking at
ever changing landscapes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:60425/images/IMG_1553.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Only one word that can describe my feeling when this
picture was taken - Liberation! And that makes this picture my
favourite&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the stories you hear growing up, how people are so bad in the
country, why a woman should never travel alone, etc. makes you so
prejudiced about people. I didn’t even have a single bad experience of that
sort (I, of course, travelled sensibly and cautiously not to
get into trouble). People turned out to be really nice and most of the
localites were curious to know why a girl from Kerala is travelling alone in the North.
I went completely mental one day and decided to take a local bus from the India-Nepal
border to Varanasi. The journey took almost 12 hours and was extremely
uncomfortable. I was the only woman in the bus. The bus driver and the
conductor made sure I never felt insecure. They made me sit in the front
seat, kept talking to me whenever they could and even offered me tea.
Well, my faith in humanity is restored, folks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People have asked me before why I like travelling. I hated that
question. One of my friends said travelling is a fad. Truth be said, I
didn’t have anything to say in my defence. I think I now have an answer.
How sometimes you start feeling that your life has started following a
routine and everything has kind of become static, is something I could
never make peace with. And I think my initial attraction towards
travelling was the absence of this feeling. Once I started travelling, I
started to enjoy observing the day-to-day life of people. People leading
their lives in manners completely different from the way we do back
home. The way of life is heavily influenced by the local culture, the
climate, the heredity, religion, and what not. You learn so much about
the history of a  place just by observing the common people. On top of
it all, the fellow travellers you meet, with so many adventures of their
own to talk about, leave you inspired and wanderlust-ing more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In four days, I am heading back home and I feel like I had to end this
journey rather abruptly, like I haven’t had enough of it.
But I think, I will never have enough of it
because road is where I belong, with changing images but one
unchanging theme - Life. I return home, not with a heavy heart
but with a lot of unforgettable experiences, to plan my next adventure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Namaste!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Day I Decided to Travel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-01-10-the-day-i-decided-to-travel.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 15:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2016-01-10-the-day-i-decided-to-travel.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It was exactly 4 months ago, on the day after I met with an accident and
was temporarily crippled, which ironically was the day of my 23rd birthday,
I made the best decision of my life. I decided to
backpack in Europe as soon as I (literally) get back on my feet and, of course,
the consulate allows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I haven&amp;rsquo;t traveled much even with my family, let
alone solo. I never realized I even had a flair for traveling till last
year, when I had my little adventure in Rajasthan. Going to Rome has
been on my bucket list since high school. Also, a bit embarrassing to admit,
I was scared to death that my parents will get me married to someone
in an year and I will never get to travel alone again. So on a sunny
Friday afternoon of September 4th 2015, I decided, just like that, to
travel to Italy the coming December and experience the European winter
and Christmas, no matter what. Boy, Am I happy I did!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With very less capability to move and having my mother taking care of me
like a 4 year old(guilty pleasures), after work, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have much to
do. So I spent a lot of my time looking up about Visa procedures, ticket fare, overall
budget, places to visit, and what not. That&amp;rsquo;s when I realized, planning
for a European is a lot of work. All the bullshit the travel agents tell
you about the Visa(which by the way no one should ever listen to,
period!), the contradicting advises you find about the same on travel
forums, etc. can almost change your mind, almost! But I kept at it.
Decided to apply for Visa by myself and started planning the entire
trip. Within a month I made a pretty good itinerary for my trip,
covering 8 countries and my time as a patient was nearing an end.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next couple of weeks were really busy. I won&amp;rsquo;t bore you with the
details of my further preparations like convincing the parents(Very
difficult), getting the Schengen Visa(Very easy), winter shopping,
booking the tickets and accommodations, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of January 11th 2016, it has been 2 weeks since I returned from my
European backpacking trip. How was my trip, you ask? Honestly, I am out
of words to describe how amazing it was!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my journey in Italy. My backpacking trail then advanced to
Austria, Hungary, Czech Republic, Germany, Netherlands, Belgium and
ended in France, from where I flew back to Bangalore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:60425/images/IMG_0480.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
&lt;em&gt;I was trying to capture the mighty alps, ended up taking a spooky selfie&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I now truly understand the term &amp;lsquo;Seeing the world&amp;rsquo;. I have heard people
saying about folks who are age old that they have seen the world. I
don&amp;rsquo;t know if you just live for a longer period you can see the world,
but if you travel for a longer period, you definitely can, in every
sense. While you travel, You don&amp;rsquo;t just see the sights, you see the people, their
culture, their way of life, their take on life, and you realize that the
world you have been living in was so small and confined. It is amazing
how much your mind opens up in such a small time span. I have never felt this
free, this independent and this hopeful ever in my life.  I feel like telling
every single person out there that the world is huge and there are a lot
of things to see and do out there. Life is too short for them all,
but start right now and cover as much as you can!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, yes, I proudly remember the day I decided to go on the trip and plan
to make more of such decisions in the years to come. My travel
adventures are a bit too long for a single blog post. More on it are
coming real soon! Stay tuned! ;-)
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Au revoir!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Future Import PeARS, Part - 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2015-09-18-from-future-import-pears-part-1.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2015 18:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2015-09-18-from-future-import-pears-part-1.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;PeARS (or Peer-to-peer Agent for Reciprocated Search, if you would prefer that) is a distributed search engine project that I got involved with very recently. It is a very interesting and ambitious idea that &lt;a href=&#34;http://aurelieherbelot.net/&#34;&gt;Aurelie Herbelot&lt;/a&gt; thought of, to make searching more secure, accurate and very much user reliant. For an official intro from the skipper herself head over to her &lt;a href=&#34;http://aurelieherbelot.net/pears/&#34;&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;. What I am trying to share via this post is the current status of the project, where we see PeARS down the road, how much we would love others to look into the project, and what not. Hopefully the first of many more come. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:60425/images/pear-logo.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###What is PeARS?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, we have innumerable people using the Internet, each one of whom has access to an enormous amount of data. We are at a point of time where the zillion Internet users can help each other out to find information we are looking for rather than depending on centralized search engines some big corporate has set up for us. That&amp;rsquo;s exactly the idea behind PeARS. Say n number of people have installed PeARS in their local machine. Over time, PeARS will index the search history of your browser(This happens locally and also you can choose what to index). Each one of these pears, that&amp;rsquo;s what we call each installed system, will have a unique profile(anonymous or other wise based on the user preference) identifiable by another pear and can share their search index which other pears can use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, Han is a skilled pilot who reads a lot of super awesome technical stuff about spaceships. He decides to index most of his browser history using PeARS and share it with other pears anonymously(he is trying to keep a low profile since Jabba the Hutt is looking for him). Luke, who just installed PeARS in his desktop, queries about Millennium Falcon. The distributional semantics algorithms in PeARS get search indices from pears which has same or similar terms. It clearly identifies Han Solo as a spaceship expert, gets his index along with others&amp;rsquo; and present it to Luke the fastest way possible. Luke starts reading about spaceships. He is not a bad pilot himself, now. :)&lt;br/&gt;
Luke try looking up about coolest lightsabers, but unfortunately none of the jedis were using PeARS. He gets redirected to Duck Duck go for the results. Over time, his search history also gets indexed locally which he decides to share. He became the most resourceful pear on lightsabers. And it goes on&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So like I mentioned earlier, it is very much reliant on the users of the big fat Internet. The links shared by each user helps PeARS rate them based on their resourcefulness on each topic and help others get most accurate results for their queries. No one tracking your search queries and no corporate telling you what to see.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It may sound incredibly ambitious, but the data each single one of us has access to makes this idea very much possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Present Status&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very much in the initial phase of the project. We have a prototype working which can index your local searches and queries from the couple of pears we have setup in our machines or from your local index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###What next?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the work is yet to be done. Presently, the system is not that efficient when it comes to performance, although search accuracy is near perfect. We are working on changing the data structures being used and making PeARS work faster. We plan an implementation very similar to BitTorrent to track and share data among the pears. We are yet to come up with the architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Who are we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are a bunch of people, who strongly believe that the future is distributed, working together to make a small step towards the next big change. The 5 of us involved with this project are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://aurelieherbelot.net/&#34;&gt;Aurelie Herbelot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://stultus.in&#34;&gt;Hrishikesh K.B.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Veesa Norman&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shobha Tyagi
&lt;br/&gt;and of course me. :)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We usually hangout at the IRC channel #pears in Freenode.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Do we need help?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What kind of question is that? Of course, we do!
&lt;br/&gt;The programming language we use is Python. We have hosted our code in Github, you can find the link below. We would be very much grateful to have people help us with developing, testing, documenting, publicizing, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details about the project to be followed in the next post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###Some links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/minimalparts/PeARS&#34;&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br/&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. &lt;a href=&#34;http://aurelieherbelot.net/pears/&#34;&gt;More about PeARS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rise above the storm, You will find the sunshine!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2015-09-02-rise-above-the-storm-you-will-find-the-sunshine/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Sep 2015 20:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2015-09-02-rise-above-the-storm-you-will-find-the-sunshine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t blogged in the past 2 years. Whenever I thought of blogging, suddenly I realized the topic I want to write about was embarrassingly trivial(not that I used to write about world changing ideas before). Even if somehow I end up making my mind to blog about some random stuff, the next immediate thought would be: &amp;lsquo;Who would care?!&amp;rsquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This made me not blog all this time, which I regret immensely. Today morning I started reading couple of my old blog posts and Boy, Was it entertaining! In some of them I was extremely naive, where as in some I was just plain dumb. As the blog posts progressed in time, I was changing in a lot many ways for good or for bad. When it ended I was so sad and so mad at myself for not blogging in the past one year specifically as this year has been one of my bests in this 23 years of existence. I have done stuff and seen stuff that I never thought I would do and see. I wish I had blogged about them right then and there. There has been storms and rains over which I rose. Can&amp;rsquo;t say I have seen the sunshine yet, but I am sure I will soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I learn from my mistakes and I believe it is better to be late than never to be. :-)&lt;br&gt;
So, I intend to start blogging again about the technology I have been using(Itching to share some bizarre bias I have towards some of them), the things I learned, and what not.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess, I am in for a fun ride this time! Adieu! :-)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used to blog **&lt;a href=&#34;http://nandajavarma.wordpress.com&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;** before. If anyone wants to checkout any of my older posts head over there or check them out in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gemiam.in/posts/&#34;&gt;All Posts&lt;/a&gt; section.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weekly update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-08-26-gsoc-weeklystatus-update-9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2013 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-08-26-gsoc-weeklystatus-update-9/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The work of mine has been correcting the reference glyph files and developing a web interface for the proposed framework. I had tried and made the reference files least buggy as possible. I have gone through the glyph names of almost all the 243 words in 4 fonts. I had to invest a lot of time on this especially due to one minor misunderstanding of mine on the multiple correct renderings of the words. And I hope it will get much refined after Rajeeshettan proof read it for 2 fonts as he has suggested.&lt;br&gt;
(I have changed the renderings of words with repham in Rachana such that the dotreph comes first. So words like these &lt;a href=&#34;http://troll.ws/image/2e3a872e&#34;&gt;http://troll.ws/image/2e3a872e&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://troll.ws/image/469dd87a&#34;&gt;http://troll.ws/image/469dd87a&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://troll.ws/image/5838dbec&#34;&gt;http://troll.ws/image/5838dbec&lt;/a&gt; although looks correct, will be in the wrongly rendered words list by harfbuzz.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next part of this weeks work was developing the web interface (Excuse my poor design, I am cleaning it up as I write). It doesn&amp;rsquo;t actually spits output to the user now or doesn&amp;rsquo;t make it easier for the user to open files. I am hoping to make it run the script well in a week&amp;rsquo;s time and don&amp;rsquo;t think it is ready yet for the review. So I would like another week to make it ready for reviewing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And finally about the C code I have added to the repo. I will start working on a new code in C++ once I am done with the webpage as I find the present code massively buggy and really inefficient. I hope I&amp;rsquo;ll be able to update it the week after next.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My code here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weekly update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-08-17-gsoc-weekly-status-update-8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Aug 2013 18:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-08-17-gsoc-weekly-status-update-8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have changed the framework interface from its previous form, although the previous front end automated_rendering_testing.py is still present in the repo. Now the new interface, rendering_testing.py, need all the file names to be provided as command line arguments. The user gets the convenience  of using the tab completion this way. The user will have to give as command line arguments 6 files (font  file, test cases file, reference file, rendering output and files to store output) and an optional directory name(if the engine is harfbuzz).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the rendering engine is harfbuzz, user can run the script generate_hb_rendering.py  along with the test cases file and font file as parameters, to create the rendered output file. If that is not the case, the user will have to create this file as well in the prescribed form.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, the algorithm that actually test the rendering was a bit buggy and was giving certain wrong outputs for words with multiple rendering engines and I have cleared this error. This feature gives correct output now for the files I tried it with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The next thing I am working on is the web interface and I am using Flask framework. Will make this code public as soon as I get the script running from the page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find the code here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weekly update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-08-11-gsoc-weekly-update-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Aug 2013 18:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-08-11-gsoc-weekly-update-6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past two weeks has been a blur with a lot of travelling and minimal Internet access. The following are the works I have been doing so far:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following modifications were asked to be made on the existing framework by my mentor after a Hangout session as part of the evaluations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Modify the comparison algorithm so as to show positive results for the words with multiple correct renderings - This modification is made. Now, the user can give multiple glyph names separated by comma in the reference file and if the rendering matches any one of these, the framework will return a positive response.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Modify the reference glyph file, adding the glyph names of words with multiple correct renderings. Also some corrections were asked to be made in the existing reference file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Modify the framework such that the user can even test by giving the file names as parameters. This one needs a little more work as I didn&amp;rsquo;t give options in argument parser for all the necessary file inputs. Will update this soon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Along with these some minor fixes were asked to be done on the script and all those are taken care of.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the further developments, planned to create a web interface for this framework. I am trying to create this interface using Flask and I am currently working on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, the framework will be implemented in C. I have added a partially working implementation of this in the repo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the completion of all these, if time permits, references for other fonts are also planned to be made.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will keep posted on further developments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Find my code here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gitlab.com/gem/automated-rendering-testing/tree/master&#34;&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weekly update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-07-28-gsoc-weekly-update-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2013 15:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-07-28-gsoc-weekly-update-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The works this week has been a little slow with college exams and assignments. This is what I have done so far this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have completed the list of reference files containing glyph names of 243 words from four fonts each. Fonts being: Rachana, Meera, Suruma and Lohit-Malayalaam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The code has been modified to equip not only harfbuzz renderings but renderings from other engines line Uniscribe, provided the user will produce the output of the rendering engine herself/himself. I have created a Python package containing 2 modules each for testing and creating output. The main script automated_rendering_testing.py  will make use of this package to test and give the final result. To test the framework, one can just run ./automated_rendering_testing and then provide the necessary  information, when asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to the tester, first it will compare the reference file and the rendering output. The it will create a file named result.txt containing the wrongly rendered words along with the number corresponding to the word in test cases&amp;rsquo; file. This file is used only to create the png file of the wrongly rendered words, if the engine is harfbuzz. Other wise this file is ignored. Now the actual output is a file test_result.txt with the format:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sl.No Word Rendering status(correct/wrong)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User can view this file, see the status and see the wrongly rendered word.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The framework works this way now: &lt;a href=&#34;http://nandajavarma.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/screenshot-from-2013-07-28-155652.png&#34;&gt;![Image]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/screenshot-from-2013-07-28-155652.png?w=650)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And this would be the output.png file. (As I chose harfbuzz here)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nandajavarma.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/screenshot-from-2013-07-28-155950.png&#34;&gt;![Image]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/screenshot-from-2013-07-28-155950.png?w=158)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And the test_result.txt file would look like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://nandajavarma.files.wordpress.com/2013/07/screenshot-from-2013-07-28-160136.png&#34;&gt;![Image]({{ site.baseurl }}/assets/screenshot-from-2013-07-28-160136.png?w=569)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The agenda for this week is to re-write the whole code in C.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My code is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weekly update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-07-20-gsoc-weekly-report-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2013 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-07-20-gsoc-weekly-report-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week my main task was to migrate my code to Python. As of now I have implemented my algorithm in Python. Here is the link to the repo : &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have expanded my test cases&amp;rsquo; list a bit. Now it has 243 Malayalam words. I have manually created files with glyph names of these test cases in four fonts: Rachana, Meera, Suruma and Lohith-Malayalam in files names rachana-glyph.txt,  meera-glyph.txt etc. (It is still a bit buggy, so haven&amp;rsquo;t pushed the latest commit of this yet).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the code basically does is, it will ask the tester which font she/he wants to test in. Say it is Meera. The code will look for the reference file which we manually create and the file with harfbuzz rendering of the test cases, names as hb_meera_rendering.txt. This file can be created by running harfbuzzrendering.py script with proper font files in the current directory. The main script rendering_testing.py will scan both these files and compare the glyph name corresponding to each word and stores the wrongly rendered words to a new list. Finally hb-view will be executed on the words inside this list and a file named output.png will be generated in the same directory that contains all the wrongly rendered words.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The baseline glyph names&amp;rsquo; files aren&amp;rsquo;t ready yet with complete glyph names of all the 243 words. Will be able to complete it within 1-2 days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weekly update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-07-14-gsoc-weekly-update-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2013 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-07-14-gsoc-weekly-update-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on generating a baseline glyphs file for 4 fonts: Rachana, Meera, Suruma and Lohith-Malayalam. I have selected some malayalam words from harfbuzz tree and Santhosh Thottingal&amp;rsquo;s test cases which I thought would be enough to test rendering problems. Then I started listing the glyph names of these files for each fonts in separate text files. To get the corresponding Unicode code point of each word, I wrote a small Java code. So I executed the script on each word, found all the code points and made 4 text files that contains the corresponding glyph names of the four fonts I mentioned earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my mentor did tell me that it is not possible to generate glyph names automatically, I wasted more than a couple of days on a Font Forge script to make it automatically output the glyph names. But that gives the glyph name only if we click on each character, which became terribly disappointing. So instead I used it to make the baseline glyphs file in the structure I want if I click on the necessary characters. But this code is trivial as far as rendering testing is concerned and will leave it out from now (Just noting it down as it wasted a very non-trivial amount of my time ;-) ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have modified the main C code such that it will ask the tester which font she wants and after choosing the one she needs it will output the result based on the words I have given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But my mentor pointed out that it looks quite messy looking at codes in 3 different languages for a single framework so I&amp;rsquo;ll be re-writing my code in Python this week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find my code here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&lt;/a&gt; (although the README is not up-to-date)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC Weekly update</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-06-29-gsoc-weekly-update-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Jun 2013 15:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-06-29-gsoc-weekly-update-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Coding period for GSoC has started the past week and I have been working on a very simple implementation of the proposal in C and two tiny bash scripts. My code is available here: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&#34;&gt;https://github.com/nandajavarma/Automated-Rendering-Testing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first thing to be done to test using these scripts is create a file that contains a set of words to be tested to see if their rendering is correct. Here I have taken a sample test data file created by SMC a while ago (ml-harfbuzz-testdata,txt). Now pass this file through the script render_test.sh along with the necessary font file. That is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;./render_test.sh ml-harfbuzz-testdata.txt /path/to/fontfile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will create a file named rendered_glyphs.txt that contains the output of hb-shape function of harfbuzz, i.e. the glyph name followed by some additional numbers (which will be ignored for now).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now create a file that contains the actual glyph names of the words in the the test data wordfile. I got the data from font forge. This has to be created manually and, as of now, obeying the following structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[glyph11,glyph12,glyph13,&amp;hellip;,glyph1n]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[glyph21,glyph22,glyph33,&amp;hellip;.,glyph2n]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also make sure that glyph names of each word is in the same order as that of the corresponding words in the test data file. I have named it orig_glyphs.txt Once this is done, we can pass the above two files through the executable of the script rendering_testing.c, say rendering_testing. That is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;./rendering_testing orig_glyphs.txt rendered_glyphs.txt&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script will compare the glyphs in order and if it find any pairs that doesn&amp;rsquo;t match, it will write to a file, result.txt, the line number in which the word appears in the test data file. Otherwise it will tell you the renderings are perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once this is done, to see the words with wrong renderings we will have to run the third script show_rendering.sh. It takes as input the result.txt file, the test data file and also the font file. That is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;./show_rendering.sh result.txt ml-harfbuzz-testdata.txt /path/to/fontfile&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This script will create png images of the wrongly rendered words in the current directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is all about my scripts. But the C code is very much inefficient. It even spits segmentation faults with some files. Once I make sure that I am on the right path after discussing with my mentor, I will be working on improving my algorithm and making this code better. That would be my next week&amp;rsquo;s work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSoC - Community engagement period</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-06-10-gsoc-community-engagement-period/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2013 18:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-06-10-gsoc-community-engagement-period/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GSoC 2013 approved project list was published on May 27th and the community engagement period was started from May 29th onwards. During this period the students are supposed to bond with their mentors, read the documentations and finalize your plans so you can have a head start with your project. The project topic for which I have got accepted for is &amp;ldquo;Automated rendering testing&amp;rdquo; and I will be completing that project under Swathanthra Malayalam Computing. I could learn a lot a new stuff so far during this community bonding period with a heavy deal of help from my mentor Rajeesh K Nambiar, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t started actual coding yet. I will try to explain my proposal status and further steps here, in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, my project idea is to create an automated way to test the rendering of Indic fonts by rendering engines like harfbuzz. The procedure I wish to follow here is quite simple. Create a test file that contains a set of words, mostly characters with ligatures that will be used for testing the rendering. Along with that I will be maintaining a file that contain the glyph infos of the words/characters in the test file for a particular font, say Malayalam font Rachana. As of now I am preparing it manually, can switch to font forge scripts if required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I have got all the test data, my main script will accept the entries in the test file and render it using Harfbuzz for the font Rachana. The words will be rendered using hb-shape and the output glyph values will be compared with the original glyph indices of these words that I have collected manually. If the glyph indices doesn&amp;rsquo;t match, an error flag will be set for that particular word. At the end of the comparisons, the words with error flag set can be rendered using hb-view and stored in another html file. This file can be looked up to see for rendering issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is what I will be implementing first. Depending on its efficiency, will move to any other solutions. In the above procedure, the most inefficient step, I think, is collecting the test file step and collecting the glyph index step. We can resolve the latter by, may be, using a scripts for extraction or using the .ttx file of the font (which is quite complex). But the former is a real issue. If the user wants to check for rendering issues in a font, she will have to create this file with a set of words manually. Will have to think of a way to overcome this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s it for now!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bangalore Diaries</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-04-29-bangalore-diaries/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2013 20:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-04-29-bangalore-diaries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I remember times when I used to eagerly wait for my school final exams to get through with, so that I can enjoy the long summer holidays that follows. I have been missing that feeling for a while now. But this year I was impatiently waiting for summer to arrive because I knew what was waiting for me this summer season. A long month ahead filled with knowledge, fun and freedom. An internship in Bangalore! But once  I reached Bangalore city, I could feel that my all my excitement was turning into ashes. My nerves started kicking in (As it always does) and I started wondering &amp;lsquo;What the heck am I doing here?&amp;rsquo;. I am joining as a temp intern in this cool Australian Software company called &lt;a href=&#34;http://bangthetable.com&#34;&gt;Bang the table&lt;/a&gt; . I don&amp;rsquo;t know Ruby on Rails or even Ruby without which basically all I am eligible to apply for is probably the post of an office boy/girl (Which is already taken, FYI). I got a small place (very small) to live which I knew I would love from the first sight of it and got three amazing roommates, who have been trying so hard to make my Hindi speaking skills better till date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I joined my office exactly on April 1st ( Which date could be more appropriate than this, eh? ). All the faces were extremely welcoming and warm, and some of which quite familiar too, most of them being mallu faces. I had great fun shooting people with laser guns on my first day itself. Thanks to Ershad for his awesome birthday treat. My timing was just perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:60425/images/bangalore.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My internship started off pretty smoothly. Although I didn&amp;rsquo;t know Ruby I managed to understand their code base to a very small extend and started poking around with it. Office has been just awesome. To add to the fun, there is a refrigerator for you to raid whenever you are hungry and a coffeemaker which refreshes you with lattes and cappachinos (which I&amp;rsquo;ll miss very badly) :-(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I completed my first week pretty smoothly and was wondering what to do during weekends in this &lt;em&gt;anjaana shehar.&lt;/em&gt; Luckily for me, as two of my friends Hrishi and Adhil were free those days, I did hang out with them and it was great fun. We just did roam around  Bangalore city (Not to mention, got lost at many points), ate good Kerala  food and happily wasted a whole day. :-D&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following weekend also I met with my friends here (more of online friends) like Jishnu, Praveen, Anivar, Joshina and many others which was basically a Swathanthra Malayalam Computing meet-up and had fun then as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the week next to it, We had our Australian directors visiting us (Again perfect timing of mine). The whole bang the table team went out, played paintball (which again involves shooting people) and had an awesome party at the end of the day. I consider myselves quite lucky that I got the chance to meet all those amazing people. That day will definitely stay in my memory for a long time to come.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That was about my office. Now coming to my hostel, it is an entirely different scene here. I have been living in hostel for the past 3 years but the hostel life here was quite different. The thing I loved the most is, the level of intimacy is really high here. I am not used to roomies who take so much care of each other just like sisters do. I am really going to miss these guys.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So what I achieved within this one month period. Difficult to answer. Definitely would have regretted if I missed this opportunity my entire life. So now gratitude time. :-) Thanks to Vamsee who offered me the internship in the first place. Thanks to my parents for letting me go, although they were a little hesitant in the beginning. Thanks to my senior from college Haris, who gave me the courage to go for it (He has been doing it for a while now and my biggest regret is that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t meet with him in person). Thanks to my friends Hrishi, Adhil, Jishnu and all the others who didn&amp;rsquo;t make me feel alone at all in this new place.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Does that sound like a pageant show winner&amp;rsquo;s speech? Ugh! To all those who keep nagging me to write, In your face! :-P)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I have packed my bags and am about to leave this place tomorrow and Boy, Am I sad going back home? :-P&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Hope the title is creative commons)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MiniDebConf at NIT-C</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-03-11-minidebconf-at-nit-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 19:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-03-11-minidebconf-at-nit-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever since I started loving FOSS, I really wanted to attend a FOSSMeet. And last month I got extremely lucky and could attend FOSSMeet at NIT-C. This year along with FOSSMeet a MiniDebConf was also arranged. A month prior to it, I was asked to give a Ruby gem packaging session at this MiniDebConf. I was quite nervous because this was the first FOSS event I ever attended and I was asked to give a session. But I knew it would be a great experience, So I decided to go with it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FOSSMeet was conducted from 22nd to 24th of February and my session was scheduled for 24th. I reached Calicut town on 23rd morning (Obviously unprepared) and when I was just about to hop into a bus to NIT, one of the MiniDebConf organizers, &lt;a href=&#34;http://swvist.github.com/&#34;&gt;Vipin&lt;/a&gt; called me and said that my session was preponed to that day afternoon. I started freaking out because I still had to prepare slides and decide what all to include in my session. As soon as I reached NIT, I had to go to my relatives&amp;rsquo; place at the NIT apartments, where I was supposed to stay for the next two days ( I preferred hostel, but whatever!). After that I rushed to NIT campus, got my speaker&amp;rsquo;s ID card from the registration counter and started roaming around the campus searching for the MiniDebConf venue. Finally I found that it was going on at the networks lab and got there. When I entered &lt;a href=&#34;http://look-pavi.blogspot.in/&#34;&gt;Pavi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://flossexperiences.wordpress.com/&#34;&gt;Shirish&lt;/a&gt; were giving talks on debian releases and stuff and I quite honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t know how to introduce myself. &amp;lsquo;Hey, I am Nandaja. I am a speaker here&amp;rsquo; didn&amp;rsquo;t sound polite enough. So I followed a guy, who assigned me a system in the lab thinking I am a delegate there. So I sat there and started preparing slides for my session until the lunch break.  Once I reached the hall were lunch was being served, I decided to socialize. I met some cool SMC people who were really easy going and friendly and then I met &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.j4v4m4n.in/&#34;&gt;Praveen&lt;/a&gt;, whom I was more than happy to meet. After the lunch, we went back to the NSL lab and there Praveen introduced me to Shirish and Pavi, two Debian gurus. It was the time for Debian installation workshop. Pavi asked me to help the delegates with the partitioning and stuff, which I tried doing and I don&amp;rsquo;t think the students who listened understood much. We clapped for the teams who successfully completed the installation. The session lasted till evening and it was supper time soon after. So my packaging session was again rescheduled for the next day. I again met some cool geeks there. There was a really nice Aaron Swartz memorial talk by Vishnu later that night. Following that was hack night and a talk by Praveen on open source contributions. It was getting too late and had to get back to the relatives&amp;rsquo; place. So I missed it (The reason why I preferred hostel).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So it was day-2 and my session was scheduled as the first event at MiniDebConf, that day. I got into NSL and heard all of them had real fun last night, albeit it wasn&amp;rsquo;t that much of a &amp;lsquo;hack&amp;rsquo; night. It was supposed to be a full day packaging session at MiniDebConf, which me and Praveen decided to do together. But as many other interesting events were happening simultaneously, only very few came. So we decided we&amp;rsquo;ll start packaging session once all other interesting events are over. But unfortunately, the students who showed up started leaving one by one. Luckily for me, a very enthusiastic girl showed up, who missed first day&amp;rsquo;s session and wanted to learn more about Debian. I started giving a private session for her. But around half an hour later, she said she has got a farewell party to attend and left (Yeah! She literally ran away :-P ). Till the lunch time we sat there chit-chatting. We even went to the 3D-Blender workshop but as soon as the speaker&amp;rsquo;s lap screen showed a windows desktop we left (Come on, It&amp;rsquo;s FOSSMeet, man!). After lunch, we exactly had 6 people at the packaging session and we decided to do it anyway. &lt;a href=&#34;http://stultus.in/&#34;&gt;Hrishi&lt;/a&gt; started off the session with an introduction to diaspora. Then me and Praveen together started explaining packaging. There were some really cool people there, like, Vamsee Kanakala, the Executive developer at Bang The Table, a government employee, whose sole intention was to attend the packaging event and four other enthusiastic students. The session proceeded pretty well and they were picking it up pretty fast. Almost by the end of the session, Vamsee asked me if I would like to do an internship at Bang The Table and I accepted the offer right away. :-) We couldn&amp;rsquo;t cover the whole packaging process because it was time for the closing ceremony. Anish, Praveen Vamsee and many others gave the feedback. Vamsee was really kind and he even mentioned my name at the feedback session. I was also asked to give the feedback and honestly I don&amp;rsquo;t remember what the heck I said there. All of us speakers got a beautiful momento. I bought a FOSSMeet t-shirt and was about to leave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just then, Vipin, &lt;a href=&#34;http://jaseemabid.github.com/&#34;&gt;Jaseem&lt;/a&gt;, Pavi, Praveen, Shirish, &lt;a href=&#34;https://joindiaspora.com/people/37c67c47e1b65ee1&#34;&gt;Akshat&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://thecodecracker.com/&#34;&gt;Jishnu&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://joindiaspora.com/u/anish&#34;&gt;Anish&lt;/a&gt; were planning to have a group dinner and invited me as well. It was pretty cool. I never though I would have so much fun hanging out with such uber geeks. After that, it was time for us to bid farewell and all of us went on our own ways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As it was late, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t go back home that day. I left Calicut the day after. Quite frankly, I was pretty sad that the FOSSMeet was over. But I was really happy too at the same time, because I made some new geeky friends, got an internship offer at Bangalore and had a lot of fun. Plans for the next MiniDebConf were going on. I am so looking forward to attend that one and hope it happens soon. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patching using quilt</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-01-07-patching-using-quilt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2013 22:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2013-01-07-patching-using-quilt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Patch files are files used to apply changes to the source code of a computer program. These changes may be for fixing bugs or for extending functionality. Quilt is a software utility for managing patches. Quilt is highly used among Linux kernal developers for managing patches. I started using quilt when I had to patch a piece of code while I was packaging for debian. Debian source packages usually use quilt. It has been incorporated into dpkg (Debian&amp;rsquo;s package manager).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, Let&amp;rsquo;s say you downloaded a debian package and found a bug in it. So you will have to create a patch and send it to the Debian developers for their review and approval.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Assuming that you&amp;rsquo;ve quilt installed (sudo apt-get install quilt) first step is to create the configuration file .quiltrc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a file named .quiltrc in your home directory and open it up in your favorite editor. Copy the following lines into the editor, save it and exit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;QUILT_PATCHES=debian/patches
QUILT_NO_DIFF_INDEX=1
QUILT_NO_DIFF_TIMESTAMPS=1
QUILT_REFRESH_ARGS=&amp;quot;-p ab&amp;quot;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quilt work with some directories. It will create a .pc/ directory and patches/ directory. As in the case of debian packages, you can find the patches you made (Or going to make) under debian/patches/ directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we will create the new patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt new this_is_my_patch.patch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next step is to let quilt know which file we are going to edit and for that the command is as follows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt add /path/to/the/file/to/edit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now open up the file in your favorite editor, make the changes, save it and exit. Alternatively, you can add and edit the file in a single step like this :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt edit path/to/the/file/to/edit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The file will open up either in nano or vim where you can make changes, save and exit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to apply the patch enter the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt refresh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now two other important commands while we are dealing with quilt is pop and push. Pop will remove a patch while push will apply it. The patches are basically arranged in a stack like form by quilt. If we do a pop, the patch we applied recently will be removed, even though we can find the patch file under patches directory. So when we do a push now, that patch will be re-applied. Commands for both these are quite straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt pop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt push&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, If you want to edit an existing patch, Make sure that the patch is applied. That is,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt push -a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(&amp;lsquo;a&amp;rsquo; as in all)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then edit the file as required and just run:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;quilt refresh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While we are building the package, We may want to remove all the patches associated with it. And to do that either we can enter the command &lt;strong&gt;quilt pop -a&lt;/strong&gt; each time we build the package or we can create a file named local-changes under debian/source/ directory containing the single line unapply-patches so that the patches will be automatically removed after a local build (Considered as a good practice. ).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;echo &amp;ldquo;unapply-patches&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt; debian/source/local-changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much the most basic steps involved. For diving in deeper (Ha! As if. ) refer : &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debian.org/doc/manuals/maint-guide/modify.en.html#quiltrc&#34;&gt;http://www.debian.org/doc/manuals/maint-guide/modify.en.html#quiltrc&lt;/a&gt; (Didn&amp;rsquo;t help me much. )&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also there are some standards we ought to follow when we are creating a patch, so that everyone can understand it&amp;rsquo;s purpose, author etc. The one I followed is DEP-3 and find more about it here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://dep.debian.net/deps/dep3/&#34;&gt;http://dep.debian.net/deps/dep3/&lt;/a&gt; . It involves just some simple steps when we add some line in the beginning of our patch file like - Description, Author, Forwarded, Date modified, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And do not forget to let git know all the changes you&amp;rsquo;ve made, if you are using git.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti virus for Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-22-anti-virus-for-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 21:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-22-anti-virus-for-linux/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Using an anti virus software in my Linux machine is something that I have not given much thought to. I know for the fact that the odds for a Linux system to get affected by a malware is pretty low. As of my understanding, the fact that Linux systems use open source software is a big bonus here. I mean, why would some one bother in sitting and writing a harmful program when everyone can see your code. Also crackers aim at a much elaborate target. I am sure they have better things to do than messing with some Linux users, which is only 2% of world computer users&amp;rsquo; population. Still, there are executable files that may get into your system via mails or flash drives. But in Linux, nothing will happen if you simply double click an executable file (provided you don&amp;rsquo;t have Wine installed). It won&amp;rsquo;t get executed unless you give it permission for execution. This is much unlikely to happen as Linux users are supposed to know what they are doing (Myself excluded!). And of course, there are many more reasons like user privileges, simplicity of kernal, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean that we don&amp;rsquo;t need an anti virus software installed. For instance, as in my case, I thought of  using an anti virus software when my windows using friends started blaming me for spreading malwares via flash drives. And also, being a music junkie, I constantly give my phone a hard time copying downloaded files to it from my computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After going through several forums, I decided to go for clamAV. It is an absolutely open source anti virus software. You can install the package clamav or clamtk (If you want the GUI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sudo apt-get install clamav&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now to start scanning, run the following command in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;clamscan -r  &lt;folder or file to be scanned&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(-r as in recursive)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now update your virus database definitions by running the command :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;freshclam&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may also want to uncomment the line that includes the path to the local socket in the clamd.conf file (/etc/clamav/clamd.conf).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we are good to go.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quick tip - Installing a software in linux using files in .run format</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-15-quick-tip-installing-a-package-in-linux-using-run-files/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Dec 2012 22:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-15-quick-tip-installing-a-package-in-linux-using-run-files/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The .run files are binary executable files. These files need to be executed to install the software. Such files are often considered as unsafe as we cannot find a way to uninstall them and we cannot say what the code will do to your system. But some games and apps are available that are packaged in this file format. Installing using .run file is rather easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all download the required .run file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in your terminal run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;wget -c &amp;lt; URL to the .run file &amp;gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Get the .run file as you wish. I just mentioned &lt;strong&gt;wget&lt;/strong&gt; here because it is one of my favorite GNU/Linux utilities. It enables a very nifty download of files from internet and the tab &lt;strong&gt;-c&lt;/strong&gt; can help you get data from a partially downloaded file. If the file to be downloaded is quite bulky and you don&amp;rsquo;t trust your Internet connection then &lt;strong&gt;-c&lt;/strong&gt; tab is what you need.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Method 1:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Go to the directory where the .run file is saved and run the following command in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;chmod +x foo.run&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I have arbitrarily named my .run file as foo.run. Here we are using +x to give permission for the owner to execute the file as a program. (If we replace +x with ugo+x, then the user, group and others will get the permission to execute that file as well.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now run the executable file, that is, run the command :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;./foo.run&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the installer will run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Method 2:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can do the same steps rather interactively as below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Right click the .run file and select properties. Under the permission tab check the box that says &amp;lsquo;Allow executing file as program&amp;rsquo; and click close.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Double click the .run file and select &amp;lsquo;Run in terminal&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will run the installer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both worked perfectly in Ubuntu 12.04. If different in other distros please let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recovering lost password in Ubuntu 12.04</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-10-recovering-lost-password-in-ubuntu-12-04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2012 20:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-10-recovering-lost-password-in-ubuntu-12-04/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, While I was trying to help my friend with his lost Ubuntu password, I explored the following two methods to do this quite easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First method is using the recovery mode. This method is pretty simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the grub menu, select the recovery mode. Then in the menu that appear, scroll down to the option &amp;lsquo;Drop to root shell prompt&amp;rsquo;. Now you will get a shell prompt with root authentication at the bottom of the screen. Now before changing the password we have to remount the root in read write mode and for that run the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;mount -rw -o remount /&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now go ahead and change the password of the corresponding user using the following command.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;passwd &lt;username&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now the prompt will ask for the new password. After entering it twice, as will be asked by the prompt, exit from the prompt by just entering &lt;strong&gt;exit.&lt;/strong&gt; Now select the resume normal booting option. Sometimes when booting into the system from recovery mode can give you a disoriented display screen and simple restarting is the solution for this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the above method worked just fine in my system, my friend didn&amp;rsquo;t have much luck in making this work in his system ( God knows why. ). So I tried another method and that is using the live CD. The steps I followed are as follow :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1. Boot into the Ubuntu live CD and select the option try Ubuntu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2. Open  the terminal and mount the partition that is the root partition for your actual Ubuntu as mount point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know the root partition, open gparted and see which drive is set as bootable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose /dev/sda1 is your root partition. Now to mount it as the mount point run the command :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sudo mount /dev/sda1 /mnt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;3. Make this mount point as root and for this we use chroot :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sudo chroot /mnt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4. Now you can proceed with changing password of the corresponding user, i.e. :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sudo passwd &lt;username&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Enter the new password as asked.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;5. Un-mount the root partition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;umount /mnt&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;6. Restart the system and now you can log in to your system with the new password.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found some more methods too, online, but the above two worked perfectly for me. So didn&amp;rsquo;t bother to experiment with anything else. Hope this works for my friend too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GNU Project Debugger</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-09-gnu-project-debugger/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2012 08:26:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-09-gnu-project-debugger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I came across a very nifty tool on my linux system. It is GNU Project Debugger a.k.a GDB. It is the standard debugger in UNIX. It lets you poke around your program and find out what is wrong with your program, if it crashed or gave you unexpected results. It can be used to debug programs written in Ada, Java, Pascal etc.( Although I haven&amp;rsquo;t tried it yet on anything other than C programs). So, yeah, it is a very powerful tool. I played around with it for a little while and it seems pretty easy. I am sure if I give it a little more effort, I sure can make best friends with GDB pretty soon. I wish I knew  GDB six months ago when I kept getting segmentation faults in my Data structures lab.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To startup GDB all you need to do is, in your terminal, go to the folder where you have the executable code of your crashed program and run the following command :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gdb &lt;exe filename&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for eg. :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gdb ./a.out&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(a.out being the default name for an executable file)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you did run that command, it will show some copyright information and finally you&amp;rsquo;ll get a (gdb) prompt. Now you can poke around your executable source code as you wish. To run the program inside gdb all you need to do is run the command &lt;strong&gt;run.&lt;/strong&gt; There are many nifty commands in there, like &lt;strong&gt;next&lt;/strong&gt;- to move around the program line-by-line, &lt;strong&gt;print&lt;/strong&gt;- to print the value of each variable, &lt;strong&gt;break&lt;/strong&gt;- to set the breakpoint (And this is a pretty good one. You can actually pause programs at a particular function or a line so that you can re-run the program n number of times from that breakpoint).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some other powerful tools in GDB are :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;info&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;continue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;backtrace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;frame&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am exploring all the cool stuffs that I can do with GDB and yeah, and it seems like I am getting the hang of it real quick.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>perl warning Setting locale failed</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-02-perl-warning-setting-locale-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Dec 2012 17:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-12-02-perl-warning-setting-locale-failed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today when I was trying to build a package on a Debian VPS, It started reporting really annoying messages like these:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;perl: warning: Setting locale failed.&lt;br&gt;
perl: warning: Please check that your locale settings:&lt;br&gt;
LANGUAGE = (unset),&lt;br&gt;
LC_ALL = (unset),&lt;br&gt;
LANG = &amp;ldquo;en_US.UTF-8&amp;rdquo;&lt;br&gt;
are supported and installed on your system.&lt;br&gt;
perl: warning: Falling back to the standard locale (&amp;ldquo;C&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I was trying to install a new package, I got them again. Eventhough it doesn&amp;rsquo;t cause any harm, a screen full of such messages really is annoying. I googled it and found out that I am not the only person with this problem. I could find a couple of solutions for this and the easiest one worked for me. Run the following command in your terminal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;export LC_ALL=C&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now it has stopped complaining. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Debian Packaging</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-11-30-debian-packaging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 18:26:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-11-30-debian-packaging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve picked a Gem and filed the ITP, it is time for you to start packaging. For this first run the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;gem2deb &lt;Gem name&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;gem2deb is actually the Ruby Debian packaging suite. It is a set of tools to create Debian packages from Ruby software distributed with RubyGems. It will automatically run the tests for Ruby1.8 and Ruby1.9 as well. For running these tests gem2deb look for a Rakefile or a .rb file or a .Yaml file inside the debian directory. Running these tests successfully has always been a headache for me. Still not at all good at it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, So once you have completed running gem2deb successfully, it is time for you to edit the changelog, copyright and control files. Inside the changelog file you will have to include the bug number of the filed ITP and the author&amp;rsquo;s name. In the copyright file, we have to include the copyright information like licence, author etc. of the actual gem as well as the debian package. Now the control file is the one I had real trouble dealing with. We have to include two neat descriptions about the Ruby library and its purpose. People decide whether to download that package or not reading this description, so make it catchy (I never could). Next check whether these files are clean using the command:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;lintian -iIEcv &amp;ndash;pedantic &amp;ndash;color auto ruby-foo*.changes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next step is to build the package using build package and pbuilder, that is, run the following commands:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;dpkg-buildpackage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;sudo pbuiler ruby-foo*.dsc&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you have made sure that there are no errors and the tests are running perfectly, Yeah, that&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it. Next step is to upload it to the mentors. For this you need an account in &lt;a href=&#34;https://alioth.debian.org/projects/pkg-ruby-extras/&#34;&gt;https://alioth.debian.org/projects/pkg-ruby-extras/&lt;/a&gt;. Mine isn&amp;rsquo;t activated yet. So I just push it to my gitorious repo. Before pushing we will have to import the file using git-import-dsc. This one also has been a tough one for me, as my knowledge in git is too vague. For more info on this step or a  any previous ones, checking out the Diaspora packaging page in debian wiki would be your best bet. Okay, So once you&amp;rsquo;ve pushed your imported file to the repo you will find three branches there, if you did it right- master, pristine-tar and upstream. And now it&amp;rsquo;s time to wait for someone to review it for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know this post would be of no use, because I&amp;rsquo;ve simply scribbled everything down in a rush. May be I&amp;rsquo;ll blog about the issues I faced at each step. But sometime later.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diaspora Packaging For Debian</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-11-29-diaspora-packaging-for-debian/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2012 22:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-11-29-diaspora-packaging-for-debian/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are the steps I followed while  packaging diaspora for debian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My ultimate guide for debian-diaspora packaging has been this piratepad document :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://piratepad.net/tu0H1eU2vH&#34;&gt;http://piratepad.net/tu0H1eU2vH&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaspora is built on Ruby on Rails platform. In Ruby programming language, the software packages are called &amp;lsquo;RubyGems&amp;rsquo; or simply &amp;lsquo;Gems&amp;rsquo;. Gems contain a packaged Ruby application or library. So basically our task is to convert this RubyGem into debian file format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are numerous number of gems upon which diaspora is depending. To complete the debian packaging of whole diaspora software we will have to package each and every one of these gems. So our first step towards packaging is select a gem which is a dependency for diaspora and that hasn&amp;rsquo;t been packaged yet. You can easily pick one from the above mentioned pirate pad document.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Make sure you pick a gem that does not have any other gems as dependencies that aren&amp;rsquo;t packaged yet. If  the gem you picked has such dependencies, then package the latter gem first and then proceed with the former.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve selected your gem, it is time to file an ITP i.e. Intent To Package. A sample ITP is here:&lt;a href=&#34;http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=691256&#34;&gt;http://bugs.debian.org/cgi-bin/bugreport.cgi?bug=691256&lt;/a&gt;. You&amp;rsquo;ll get all the information regarding your gem from rubygems.org or from the corresponding upstream file at github. We have to mail our ITP to the debian bug tracking system specifying the package name and a short description as the subject line. Never use rich text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you&amp;rsquo;ve send in your ITP and you got the confirmation, you are good to go with your packaging. It is quite natural that you will end up sending a buggy ITP receiving an error message. But BTS is really easy to work with and I got all such information regarding BTS from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.debian.org/Bugs/server-control&#34;&gt;http://www.debian.org/Bugs/server-control&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So here ends the preps regarding the gem, you need to do before getting started with packaging.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will get to the fun stuff in my next post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more links on packaging &lt;a href=&#34;http://resident.dyndns.info/content/wordpress/?p=282&#34; title=&#34;Nadir&#39;s blog&#34;&gt;go here&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diaspora</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-11-02-diaspora-im-lovin-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2012 08:26:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-11-02-diaspora-im-lovin-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Howdy,
Social networking is an experience that most of us do love. The most recent addition to this colossal world of social networking is diaspora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diaspora is a free personalized web server that can be installed and implemented as a distributed social network. In simple words, we own our own social networking site (More or less) . Unlike the other social networking sites, where the members are treated as mere products,in diaspora we are our own masters. Many pods/servers are maintained by numerous private groups/ individuals all around the world. We can create our account in any one of them or we can opt to run our own pod. And as it is distributed, We can connect to people with account in any other pods. Pretty cool, huh?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So if you are fed up of  money sucking site maintainers manipulating our data, love open source or are looking for a new social networking experience then Knock yourselves out! My account is in joindiaspora.com. I opted this one because this is the pod maintained by the original debian developers themselves and I found the start page and all pretty cute.
As it is an open source project which has started only very recently, it definitely miss many features that are provided by many other social networking sites. But on the bright side, look at the privacy that diaspora provides us. We can choose which all data are to be gone public, which all data are to be shown in our profile and which all data we want to see rather than someone else choosing all of the above for us. It&amp;rsquo;s widget is quite similar to that of some popular social networking sites. So there won&amp;rsquo;t be any trouble getting started because the environment is quite familiar. Also the like, comment and share utilities are  available. It definitely miss the tagging images functionality. You can consider it as a hit or miss, but I think it&amp;rsquo;s a hit because if we want our picture to be seen then we can simply re-share it. No need of other people tagging in our name. See I get to decide that too. In diaspora, instead  of add friend or add to circle we have &amp;lsquo;Add contact&amp;rsquo; option and we can choose there itself  which contact  list it goes to. Instead of  &amp;lsquo;Home&amp;rsquo;, here it is stream. Also the share box is much cooler and easier to work with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay! May be I&amp;rsquo;m bragging, because I am a FOSS enthusiast. But still, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know unless you try it. So I recommend you all to try diaspora.
You can find my  profile  in joindiaspora.com :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://joindiaspora.com/people/b172ada9583dd0c5&#34;&gt;https://joindiaspora.com/people/b172ada9583dd0c5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more info about Diaspora:&amp;lt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diaspora_%28software%29&#34;&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diaspora_%28software%29&lt;/a&gt;
So hail Diaspora.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hail FOSS.
Cheers Ya all.. :-)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello, World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-10-30-helloworld/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Oct 2012 08:26:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:60425/post/2012-10-30-helloworld/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Blogging! Not my cup of tea, probably. But still giving it a try.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheers.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>