<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>India on Nandaja.</title>
    <link>https://example.com/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in India on Nandaja.</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>cn</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 18:58:42 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://example.com/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Travelling In And Around North India</title>
      <link>https://example.com/post/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Sep 2016 18:58:42 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://example.com/post/2016-09-04-backpacking-in-and-around-north-india.markdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I quit my job, everyone kept asking - ‘So, what next?’ to which I&#xA;politely replied - ‘Nothing decided yet’. In my mind, I already had the&#xA;plan though. I wanted to travel. Where to? I knew that as well. I wanted&#xA;to explore my vast and diverse country. I thought I will finish off my&#xA;country first and then will go on to the South-East Asian countries, as if it is&#xA;even possible to “finish off” seeing India. I have been on the road for&#xA;a couple of months now and I haven’t even scratched the surface of the&#xA;country. Every single place I have been so far had some novelty or other&#xA;to offer. Looking back, this journey has been life changing. The&#xA;experiences I have had - some good and some bad, gave me a lot of&#xA;perspective on my own life. Moreover, I realised how perfectly content I am just&#xA;being with myself. I always used to think I was an introvert. I was a&#xA;bit shy in public and never felt comfortable in a big group. Travelling&#xA;alone, when I got so comfortable being with myself, I started&#xA;getting along with people so well. Someone wise once told me - ‘If you&#xA;are not happy being with yourself, you can never be happy being with&#xA;other people’. I understand what he meant now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
